[Music]
welcome back to the channel
this video is going to be a recreation
of one of ben and jerry's
new flavors this is the cookie dough
core it is
the rain dough you can see that there
you go
the raindo version so this is
a vanilla cookie dough core
with multi-colored chocolate chips in a
vanilla base
that's one of their new flavors they do
a chocolate one as well but for this one
we're just going to do the
vanilla one i say just because i haven't
actually done any of this
beforehand i've not made the cookie
dough before
i've not done the chocolate treatment
before so what you're going to see is
the good
bad and ugly version of someone that's
never done it so
hope you enjoy this video let's get
stuck in and do it
the base is a very simple philly style
ice cream so put your milk cream and
sugar into a pan
and then slowly heat it up then add your
vanilla before it gets too hot
just let that sugar dissolve and then
take it off the heat and put it in the
fridge to chill
leave it in there for three or four
hours something like that
[Music]
next we're going to go on to the cookie
dough take your butter that in my case
was still way too hard
add your sugar to it and then whisk it
and make sure that it goes all over the
kitchen
if you use butter that's actually soft
enough then make sure it's combined
really nicely that you can see here
at that stage you can start adding your
other ingredients so there's a splash of
salt in there
and then you need to add your sprinkles
and your flour
now for this cookie dough you need to
make sure you use heat treated flour now
i did mine in the microwave so i'll put
a link below
as to where i got those instructions
it's really quick and simple but you can
also do it in the oven if you like
once you've added all your sprinkles
what i've done is i've taken a tube
and filled that with the cookie dough as
you can see here this is an absolute
experiment
no idea if this is going to work or not
so we'll soon see
i'm also going to make an alternative
call this one's not being kept in the
fridge or freezer or anything but i'm
just going to wrap it up in some cling
film
just in case the tube idea doesn't work
the next stage is to try and create
those multi-colored
i'm not going to do the multi-colored
but the colored chocolate
drops now if you look on the actual tub
for the ben and jerry's
it doesn't say chocolate it says
chocolate flavor so what we've got is
we've got the decker melts here we're
going to melt them in a microwave so you
can get that nice
loose consistency and i've put a baking
pan covered before in the freezer
now i've done this just so i can dab the
chocolate on there and hopefully it will
go hard very quick
as you can see it works okay with a
spoon but if you use a piping bag
it does make life much easier halfway
through i actually have to put it all
back in the freezer then once completed
again mac in the freezer for just 5-10
minutes
and then scrape it off put it in the tub
put it aside once you've done all that
pour yourself a drink because you've
probably made a massive mess in the
kitchen like i have and there's at least
an hour's worth tidying up to do
as you can tell by this video like i
said i've never done this before
it turned out okay i don't know what the
cookie dough is going to be like i don't
know whether it's going to come out the
tube
who knows we're going to get around to
that in a second fingers crossed
as always we're going to take the base
out the fridge 20 minutes before we want
to churn it
and we're going to add in our milk
powder
again two tablespoons and then pop it
back in the fridge for 20 minutes
finally take it out again give it a good
stir and then pop it in your machine to
churn
so take about 20 minutes as normal
something like that i like to
pre-cool my machine for 10 minutes but
you don't have to do that if you don't
want to
once your ice creams are fully chained
and ready to go load up your tub now
i've lined the tub
with cling film again because i want to
do a
cross-section cut i don't want to
destroy the tub because i love my wife's
designs
so that's what we're going to do load in
your ice cream add your chocolate
chips looking at the ben and jerry's
version i've not had it i can't get hold
of it yet
the chocolate chips are sided so one
side's one color one side to the other
so that's what we're going to try and
attempt here
right it's been seven hours something
like that
in the freezer let's take it out and
see what it looks like i'm gonna try and
cut it down the middle give me a bit of
a cross-section
so we can see the call
there you go i'm quite surprised that
the result actually
i've never really done anything with
cookie dough i'm not a massive fan of
cookie dough
my wife loves it so she'll end up eating
most of this tub i'm sure
but okay you know looking at the ben and
jerry's pictures
they're little chocolate drops they're
two different
multi-colored swells i haven't done that
i'd probably fail
worse than i have just doing these
single color ones but
that core that's bang on the money that
is
you can see the little rainbow sprinkles
in there the vanilla ice cream is really
good i
guarantee you that ben and joe's vanilla
ice cream is not gonna be like this
it's a very luxurious
vanilla ice cream
the vanilla bean paste in that gives you
a really intense vanilla flavor
the chocolate i mean you know i quite
chocolate in the loosest possible sense
it's kind of like chocolate flavoured
flavored
you don't taste anything it literally
tastes of nothing
but that's not the point of these the
point of those is to add a splash of
colour
which you get and the actual cookie
dough itself
it's not gone rock solid which is great
you can you know you can dig right in
and
get some bits out but uh is this a
success
i think it is i think we've done really
really well to recreate this core
if you ever bought a ben and jerry's
core version of ice cream
you're usually a little bit disappointed
let's be honest when you dig in
especially with the caramel ones
and you dig in there's basically nothing
in there
at least if you do this yourself you can
dictate how much of that core ingredient
you put in
so give this one a try
if you do send us a picture let us know
how it goes
because we can't get this flavor over
here yet
grab it if you can get it where you are
if you fancy doing a cross-section of it
then you know
feel free but don't ruin your tub just
because of it but i'd love to see what
the actual inside of a ben
jerry's version looks like be
interesting to compare the two
anyway thanks very much for watching
this next video
is gonna be another vegan one i'm gonna
get a little bit fancy on that one
though so uh
i hope you join us for that one remember
to like and subscribe
and we'll see you next time thanks very
much for watching